scan.co.uk 2018-12-25

# Privacy Information | SCAN UK

### We respect your privacy

We at Scan Computers International Limited respect the privacy of our visitors and are committed to preserving your online safety and privacy at any time you visit or communicate with our site. Scan are the 'data controller' of the personal data that you provide to us.

Our Privacy Information and Terms of Use offers you a thorough explanation regarding your personal data provided to us or any data we may collect from you.

Please feel free to contact us with queries, requests, or comments you may have about our Privacy Information. We welcome any communication via our online query system. 

You can also contact us at Scan Computers International Ltd, 25 - 28 Enterprise Park, Middlebrook, Horwich, Bolton, BL6 6PE

This Privacy Information is updated from time to time; therefore, it should be reviewed occasionally. Last update: 24-May-2018

## Purposes of Processing

Personal data is collected and processed during the operation of our website, we only store personal data for as long as required. We may use third party service providers to help with this processing, they act as a 'data processor' on our behalf and only use the data collected in ways we specify for our own purposes. The categories of third parties which we work with include IT service providers, Delivery Agents, Payment Service Providers and Marketing Companies.

We only process the minimum personal data necessary and use industry standard data masking techniques where possible (pseudonymisation / anonymisation). We have outlined some of this activity and the parties involved (data processors unless otherwise stated) below:

### Improving the usability of our website

We process data such as online identifiers and behavioural data in order to measure performance and improve the user experience of our website.

Our website uses Webtrends to provide A/B testing functionality. This lets us see the impact of changes to our website by measuring things like number of clicks on a button. We aggregate the data and use statistical analysis to decide which change performed better. We don't use this data to identify you directly. 

Our web site may use SessionCam for analysis. SessionCam is a product that has been developed by SessionCam LTD. SessionCam may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, page scrolling and any text keyed into website forms. The information collected does not include bank details or any sensitive personal data. Data collected by SessionCam from our website is for our internal use only. The information collected is used to improve our website usability and is stored and used for aggregated and statistical reporting. 

You can set your preferences around this type of processing on our [privacy dashboard](https://secure.scan.co.uk/web/privacy-dashboard). 

### Traffic & Security

When you browse our website the requests are sent via the Cloudflare network. Cloudflare will process online identifiers in order to ensure that our traffic is genuine and prevent cyber-attacks such as a Denial of Service attack. We will also keep logs of requests to our website, the data collected may include your IP addresses.

### Cookies

We use cookies on our website to enable essential functionality and enhance your experience when browsing our site. You can find more information in our cookie policy

### Reviews / Q&A

The reviews and Q&A feature on our website is provided by Bazaarvoice, when you leave a review Bazaarvoice will collect this data and make quality control checks before publishing it to our website.

### Creating an Online Account

When you create an online account with us you provide us with information that we use to remember you and enable you to check out faster. This also gives you access to features such as Order History, Saved Baskets.

We do not have the ability to recover the password you specify and read it in plain text. This is stored in a one-way hashed format which is computed using the key derivation function PBKDF2, using a randomly generated salt and very high number of iterations.

### Contacting Us

When you contact us we will process the data you provided, our agents may access information on your account in order to serve you and handle your query. We use Zendesk Chat to provide our live chat system. 

### Placing an Order

When you place an order with us we may need to share your data with third parties in order to process that order.

We will need to provide your delivery and contact information to the delivery agent that you have chosen at checkout (e.g. DPD, UPS).

The payment information you provided will be used by our payment service providers in order to complete the transaction. Any credit card details are securely stored with our Payment Service Provider (Braintree / PayPal). For display purposes, we store your credit card number (PAN) in a masked format in line with PCI standards. If you have chosen to save your card to your account, we use a token provided by Braintree to authorise your credit card on subsequent orders, you can delete any saved cards using [My Account](https://secure.scan.co.uk/web/myaccount). 

We will contact you by email to provide you with order status updates, when you give us your mobile telephone number we may send you SMS messages for important information about your order. 

After your order has been delivered we may contact you to ask you to provide feedback or leave a review of the products you purchased.

### Competition

We run regular competitions and use a service called Gleam to collect the entries. Gleam act as a data processor on our behalf and only collect data for Scan Computers use. We will only use this information in order to administer the competition (e.g. choose and contact a winner), and use aggregated data for analytical and statistical purposes. We will ask for your consent when entering a competition to do this. 

### Email Marketing

We send our email newsletters ('Scanshots') to our customers who have given their consent to receive them. We also send these to existing customers who have previously "soft" opted-in and have not unsubscribed. We make it very easy to unsubscribe or set your preferences. You can: 

  * Unsubscribe by using the link provided in any Scanshot email you receive
  * Press "unsubscribe" in your email client (supported email clients only) 
  * Change your preferences on [My Account](https://secure.scan.co.uk/web/myaccount)
  * Use our [email preferences](https://secure.scan.co.uk/web/email-preferences) page

We make every effort to ensure you are still interested in receiving these emails and may automatically unsubscribe you if you do not read the emails, or we experience errors sending them to you. We recommend you add us to your safe senders list to prevent this. 

### Tailored Advertising

We share data which has undergone pseudonymisation about the products you have viewed or items that you have added to your basket with trusted third party advertisers such as Criteo. We act as joint data controllers for this processing. This allows us to show you relevant ads that may be of interest to you. You can opt-out of this processing using the [privacy dashboard](https://secure.scan.co.uk/web/privacy-dashboard), if you do this you will still see advertisements online but they will be less relevant to you. 

If you would like to opt-out of processing by third party advertisers in general please visit <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices> and <https://www.google.com/settings/ads>

## Privacy Dashboard

We want you to have control over the way we use your personal data. Using our [privacy dashboard](https://secure.scan.co.uk/web/privacy-dashboard) you can specify your preferences and control whether you would like to opt-out of certain types of processing, such as session recording. 

## Lawful Basis for Processing

We process personal data under the following lawful bases:

###  Contractual Performance 

We will process your personal data in order to fulfil our contractual obligations to you. For example when processing an order you have placed with us. 

### Legal Obligation

We may process your personal data under legal obligation where we are required to do so by common law or statutory obligation.

### Legitimate Interests

We may process your personal data in order to meet our legitimate interests, when doing so we have considered whether that processing is necessary and balanced it against your interests, rights and freedoms. In some cases you have the right to object.

Some of our legitimate interests are:

  * Improving customer experience with our website
  * To measure and analyse the performance of our website
  * To prevent fraudulent activity on our website
  * To protect data & network security and ensure data integrity
  * To prevent cyber attacks
  * To market our goods and services to our customers

### Consent

In some cases, we process your personal data when you have given us consent to do so. If you have given us consent then you can contact us at any time to withdraw it.

## Your Rights

Under data protection law and GDPR you have a number of rights:

  * The right to access
  * The right to rectification
  * The right to erasure
  * The right to restrict processing
  * The right to data portability - you can download your data using [My Account](https://secure.scan.co.uk/web/myaccount)
  * The right to object

If you wish to exercise any of these rights you can contact us via our help centre, we will endeavour to respond to you as soon as possible and within one calendar month.

## Personal Data Storage

Locations outside the European Economic Area may be used for transferring data we collect about you, e.g. with third-party data processors that rely on cloud services hosted in the US. We take all reasonable action to ensure the safety of your personal data in agreement with this Privacy Information and ensure appropriate safeguards are in place. Any information we are provided will be stored on secure servers. We take all reasonable action to protect information sent to us electronically. Where applicable you may be given access to sections of our site that require a password. You are responsible for the passwords safety and confidentiality. 

## Right to Complaint

If you are unhappy about the way we handle your personal data then you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority. In the UK this is the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), you can contact them via their website <https://ico.org.uk/>
